#### LINDSAY BORDELON

# LCBORDELON@GMAIL.COM

(225) 505-3694

# PROFESSIONAL OVERVIEW

Safety-focused energy professional with progressive experience in environmental project management, environmental compliance audits, compliance reporting, database management, and application development; detail oriented professional comfortable in small and large teams of agencies, contractors, vendors, developers and stakeholders, with a focus on operational excellence at all levels;

#### EDUCATION

B.Sc. Coastal Environmental Science • Louisiana State University • May 2012

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Kinder Morgan

Manager - EHS

June 2016 - Present

EHS Systems – LMS

Manager of the company wide learning management system (LMS). Duties include:

- Management of the companywide LMS and regulatory/policy updates to training
- Coordination with the LMS third party vendor, DuPont Sustainable Solutions
- Leader of the KM Training Technical Working Group to drive training best management practices and corporate KM goals and initiatives
- Lead and manage KM IT to develop, create, and implement systems and applications
- Creation of application technical requirements and test cases
- Tracking of IT bug and enhancement items via the Jira ticket system
- Management of the Training Matrices Management System (TMMS) application
- Development of corporate required training content
- Interaction with varying levels of KM personnel to accomplish corporate training initiatives

#### Kinder Morgan

EHS Specialist I

February 2014-June 2016

Assessment and audit lead responsible for the following duties:

- Coordinate and manage field environmental, health and safety compliance audits at company owned and operated facilities to ensure compliance with State and Federal regulations, and company policies
- Familiar with OSHA, EPA, USCG, DOT, and state regulations and interpretations
- Prepare audit reports, including tracking and documentation of findings to completion using the Audit Action Tracker (AAT) system
- Maintenance of the AAT system to streamline findings based on citation, evidence, and corrective action

### Conestoga-Rovers & Associates

**Environmental Scientist** 

May 2012-February 2014

Environmental Scientist for multi-disciplinary projects for various oil and gas clients and sites.

#### LINDSAY BORDELON

LCBORDELON@GMAIL.COM (225) 505-3694

CERTIFICATIONS

University of Denver Coding Bootcamp (Fullstack)

Certification est compl March 2021

Associate Safety Professional (ASP)

Certification December 2017-Present

#### **AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS**

#### EnGen Class of 2019

Colorado Oil & Gas Association

2019

EnGen is a year long executive leadership program hosted by the Colorado Oil & Gas Association. EnGen features interaction with industry executives, panels of speakers regarding various industry topics, one field day, and one charity day. Completed a summit project regarding automation in the oil & gas industry; specifically digitization, artificial intelligence, and machine learning.

# 2018 Verdantix HSE Technology Innovation Award Winner

Oil & Gas Sector May 2018

Awarded the Verdantix Health, Safety and Environmental (HSE) Technology Innovation Award in the Oil & Gas sector for our use of the DuPont LMS to reduce overdue training from 69% in 2013 to 0.14% as of October 1, 2018 (0.00% as of January 1 2020). The Verdantix HSE Innovation Awards recognize the people and organizations that are instrumental in launching successful, innovative technologies which facilitate management of the HSE function to deliver superior results. Kinder Morgan was one of 18 Oil & Gas companies in competition for the award and was unanimously selected as the award winner.

# Speaker - 2018 DuPont Safety Forum

Virginia Beach, VA August 2018

Main stage speaker at the 2018 DuPont Safety Forum. Presented 'Kinder Morgan & the DuPont LMS' - a case study explaining the relationship between KM and the DuPont LMS and how this relationship was leveraged to reduce overdue training from 69% in 2013 to 0.14% in July 2018.

## REFERENCES PROVIDED UPON REQUEST